<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources >
   
   <string name="app_name">Milan</string>
    
    <string name="overview_st">"Overview

Milan (mĬlăn´, –än´), Ital. Milano, Lat. Mediolanum, city (1991 pop. 1,369,231), capital of Lombardy and of Milan prov., N Italy, at the heart of the Po basin. Because of its strategic position in the Lombard plain, at the intersection of several major transportation routes, it has been since the Middle Ages an international commercial, financial, and industrial center. Today Milan is Italy's second largest city after Rome and its economic heart. It has the highest per capita income in Italy. Manufactures include textiles, clothing, machinery, chemicals, electric appliances, printed materials, motor vehicles, airplanes, and rubber goods. The city has a large construction industry, and it is one of the most important silk markets in Europe. 

Milan is elegant, chaotic, and utterly beguiling in turn. Traffic chokes the streets, and it can be bitterly cold in winter and stiflingly hot in summer, yet its architecture is majestic and the robust Northern Italian cuisine warming. It’s a world-beater on the international fashion stage, the banking capital of Italy, a wealthy city of glamorous people and stylish shopping streets.

And Milan has history. As well as the Roman ruins, the soaring duomo and its majestic piazza, the galleries are stuffed with priceless artworks, and there are ancient churches, medieval castles, Renaissance palaces, and amazing contemporary architecture to admire.

In 2015 Milan welcomes 29 million visitors for the 6-month-long citywide extravaganza that is the World Expo. Running from May 1 through October 31, the theme of this exposition is feeding the planet. At press time, the construction of a new exhibition complex was well underway around Pero and Rho, just northwest of the centro storico. Here a new cluster of world-class architecture has grown up in the CityLife district, headed by the innovative towers built by archistars Arata Isozaki, Daniel Libeskind, and Zaha Hadid.  Points of Interest  The most striking feature of the city is the Duomo, the large, white-marble cathedral (1386–1813), which shows traces of many styles (especially Gothic). It is elaborately ornamented, with 135 pinnacles and more than 200 marble statues. A statue of the Madonna is on the highest pinnacle (354 ft/108 m). Other points of interest in Milan include Brera Palace and Picture Gallery (17th cent.), which includes major works by Mantegna, Bellini, Piero della Francesca, and Raphael; the Castello Sforzesco (15th cent., with 19th-century additions), which houses a museum of art; the Church of Santa Maria delle Grazie (1465–90), containing the famous fresco, the Last Supper, by Leonardo da Vinci; the Basilica of Sant' Ambrogio (founded in the 4th cent., rebuilt in the 11th–12th cent.); the Ambrosian Library, which houses a rich collection of paintings; the Church of Sant' Eustorgio (9th cent.); the Leonardo da Vinci Museum of Science and Technology; the gallery of modern art; and the Poldi Pezzoli Museum, with paintings by Boticelli, Pollaiuolo, Mantegna, and Piero della Francesca. Long a center of music, Milan has a conservatory and a famous opera house, Teatro alla Scala (opened in 1778). Between the Duomo and La Scala is the 130-year-old Galleria, an enclosed four-story glass-roofed arcade that contains shops and eateries and is a popular gathering place. The city also has three universities and a polytechnic institute.   History  Probably of Celtic origin, Milan was conquered by Rome in 222 BC In later Roman times it was the capital (AD 305–402) of the Western Empire and the religious center of N Italy. In 313 Constantine I issued the Edict of Milan, which granted religious toleration. From 374 to 379 the city's bishop was St. Ambrose, known for the liturgy he wrote and for his eloquence. Milan was severely damaged by the Huns (c.450) and again by the Goths (539) and was conquered by the Lombards in 569.  In the 12th cent. it became a free commune and gradually gained supremacy over the cities of Lombardy. From the 11th to the 13th cent. Milan suffered from internal warfare between rich and poor, from the Guelph and Ghibelline strife, and from the enmity of rival cities, which assisted Emperor Frederick I in destroying it (1163). As a member of the Lombard League, Milan later contributed to the defeat of Frederick I at Legnano (1176). The city's independence was recognized in the Peace of Constance (1183). In the 13th cent. Milan lost its republican liberties; first the Torriani, then the Visconti (1277) became its lords. Galeazzo Visconti received (1395) the title of duke of Milan from the emperor, and under him the duchy became one of the most important states in Italy. After the death of the last Visconti (1447) the Sforza became dukes of Milan. The city flourished until it became involved in the Italian Wars and passed under Spanish domination (1535).  At the end of the War of the Spanish Succession, Austrian rule of Milan was established (1713–96). Napoleon I made the city the capital of the Cisalpine Republic (1797) and of the kingdom of Italy (1805–14). In 1815 Milan again came under Austria. It was a leading center throughout the Risorgimento; after five days of heroic fighting in 1848 the citizens of Milan succeeded in expelling the Austrians, who returned, however, a few months later. In 1859 the city was united with the kingdom of Sardinia. Its industrial importance grew after it was incorporated (1861) into Italy. In World War II Milan suffered widespread damage from Allied air raids; many significant buildings were damaged beyond repair.

City Info

Milan (Milano in Italian), the motivating force behind the financial sector of Italy, is the second largest city in the country behind Rome. The city holds a strong position as the capital of the Province of Milan as well as the regional capital of the Region of Lombardy. While Rome does enjoy its position as the administrative capital of Italy, Milan makes it presence felt strongly in many areas mainly in the fashion industry. Along with the powerful names of Paris, New York and London, Milan is referred as one of the fashion capitals of the world. The heart of the financial hub of Italy lies in Milan with the National Stock Exchange located in the city. The urban look of the city may not exactly make heads turn as it does with other Italian cities that have long Roman history emotionally involved with them. Nevertheless, the fashion expositions, nightlife, Italian food and the metropolitan area of Milan provide the futuristic outlook of Italy, which attracts many youngsters. Also, it’s like a base camp for exploring Northern Italy’s tourist cities which include the Alps.

Milan might wrongly represent itself as an expensive destination, which is untrue considering there are lots of places in the city where one can have a cup of coffee without losing lots of pennies. Also it’s not only the place where fashion conscious people throng to get a place at the first row of Milan Fashion Week, but also where museums, churches and theatres can provide an insight to the forgotten ancient generation. Window shopping, appreciating art pieces, viewing the city through the horizon of the mountains or going on evening strolls can be as pleasurable and romantic.

Milanese people are one of most hard working people on the earth and the believers of the saying “Work Hard  and  Party Harder”. The Milan Metropolitan Area has the highest density of urban and industrial population in Italy and one of the biggest in Europe. The area is a part of the “Blue Banana” cities in Europe.

Country	Italy

Capital	Roma / Rome
City	Milano / Milan
Region	Lombardy
Province	Province of Milan
Area	

•	City: 182 km2 (70.3 sq mi)
•	Urban: 1,982 km2 (765.3 sq mi)

Population	

•	Density: 7,159/km2 (18,541.7/sq mi)
•	Urban: 3,076,643
•	Called: Milanesi or Meneghini

Time Zone	CET (UTC+1) Summer: CEST (UTC+2)

Official Language	Italian, Western Lombard language (Insubric), Milanese
"</string>
<string name="CityFacts">"CityFacts

Milan is one of Italy's most fashionable cities and one of the richest cities in Europe but it also holds several historic and artistic attractions, including the largest Gothic cathedral in the world, the Last Supper painting, and the famous La Scala Opera House. Travelers to Milan will find a fast-paced, glamorous city with a thriving cultural scene and a top city for shopping. Although the city was heavily bombed during World War II, much of it was rebuilt.

Milan - the fashion capital of the world and the economic capital for Italians is a lovely place located in Italy. If you are looking for a vacation with a difference, Milan is the place for you. This place is full of mystical monuments, palaces, etc. that must be visited when you are roaming around in Milan. But of all the things in Milan, the one thing to look out for is the clothing choices, be it designer wear or flea-market goodies. With a wide variety to choose from, visitors are sure to be spoilt for choice. Milan is also famous for the world-renowned La Scala Opera house, Leonardo Da Vinci's Last Supper and the Gothic Cathedral Duomo. Be it nightlife, great food or a thriving fashion industry, Milan has a lot in store in terms of tourism. Want to know some more interesting facts about Milan? Then check out these fun facts about Milan.

Fast Facts
 
Country: Italy
Continent: Europe
Established In: 400 BC
Established By: Celts
Population: 1,347,298
Area: 181.76 km2
Elevation: 120m
Demonym: Milanese
 
Fun Facts About Milan

•	Milan is considered to be the fashion center of the world. The place has headquarters and businesses of some of the leading international designers, which include Gucci, Prada, Armani, Versace, and Dolce  and  Gabbana.

•	Milan experiences some of the most bearable summer’s around the world according to a recent survey in 2010.

•	The major industries that help in the growth of the economy of Milan are Textile manufacturing, Chemical manufacturing, Food manufacturing, Tourism, Shipbuilding, etc.

•	Milan is the capital of Lombardy and the second-largest city in Italy.

•	Milan is considered to be the 12th most expensive city in the world.

•	The prime language spoken here is Italian, followed by English, French, Chinese and Dutch.

•	The ‘Gran Premio di Monzo’, the Italian version of the Grand Prix, is held in Milan annually.

•	During the late 18th century and all through the 19th, Milan was an important center for intellectual discussion and literary creativity.

•	The most important religion here is Catholic. Other religions practiced here include Buddhism, Judaism, Islam and Protestantism.

•	Milan is credited to be the second largest city in Italy. The total population of Milan is around 1.5 million.

•	Dumo Cathedral is a major tourist attraction of Milan. It is one of the biggest Gothic Cathedrals in the world.

•	Milan is home to Teatro alla Scala, Europe’s premier Opera House with a seating capacity of over 2,000.

•	The ‘Castello Sforzeco’ in Milan, is an ancient fortress built in 1368, which later became a noble Renaissance abode.

•	The third largest cathedral in the world, the ‘Duomo’, is situated in Milan and it took nearly 4 centuries to complete. Now that takes some patience and dedication, doesn’t it?

•	After Milan was battered by World War II, the city attracted immigrants on a colossal scale. About 15Percent of Milan’s population is foreign born..

•	Do you know Milan has its very own ‘Chinatown’ in a district called Via Paola Sorpi? Many of the workers here are immigrants from China and previously worked in the silk industry.

•	Milan has a strong provincial cuisine. Risotto is the major course of the city as compared to pasta in the other Italian cities.

•	One-third of the Filipinos around the world, live in Milan.

•	One of the world's oldest car racing circuits, Monza Formula One, is located near the city of Milan. The total capacity for the races is around 137,000 spectators now, although in the 1950s, the stands could hold more than 250,000 people.

•	Milan is the only city in Europe whose football teams have won both the European Cup and the Intercontinental Cup. Both the teams play at Giuseppe Meazza - San Siro Stadium.

•	The ‘Teatro alla Scala’ Opera house was built in 1776 and is considered to be one of the biggest opera houses in the world.

•	Milan has the highest per capita income in Italy.

Milan Location:

Milan is in northwest Italy in the Lombardy region, about 30 miles south of the Alps. It is very near the Lake district, including Lakes Como and Maggiore. See Lombardy Map. From Milan, Rome is reachable on a fast train in as little as 3 hours and Venice in less than 3 hours. See our Milan to Venice Train Itinerary for suggested stops enroute.

Milan, Italy:

Milan is one of Italy's most fashionable cities and one of the richest cities in Europe but it also holds several historic and artistic attractions, including the largest Gothic cathedral in the world, the Last Supper painting, and the famous La Scala Opera House. Travelers to Milan will find a fast-paced, glamorous city with a thriving cultural scene and a top city for shopping. Although the city was heavily bombed during World War II, much of it was rebuilt.

Milan Location:

Milan is in northwest Italy in the Lombardy region, about 30 miles south of the Alps. It is very near the Lake district, including Lakes Como and Maggiore. See Lombardy Map. From Milan, Rome is reachable on a fast train in as little as 3 hours and Venice in less than 3 hours. See our Milan to Venice Train Itinerary for suggested stops enroute.

Transportation to Milan:

Milan has 2 airports. Malpensa, to the northwest, is a big international airport. The Malpensa Express train connects the airport to the stations of Centrale and Cadorna, near the historic center. The smaller Linate airport to the east serves flights from Europe and within Italy and is connected to the city by bus service.

The main train station, Milano Centrale at Piazza Duca d' Aosta, links to major cities in Italy and western Europe. Domestic and international bus lines arrive in Piazza Castello.

Public Transportation in Milan:

Milan has very good public transportation, including buses, trams, and an extensive metro system. For a map of the public transportation routes in central Milan and how to use them, see our Milan Transportation Map.

Milan Weather - When to Go:

The city can be very hot and humid in summer but winters are not too severe. Find out more about Milan's average monthly temperatures and rainfall on Milan Weather and Climate.

Milan Food and Hotels:

Two famous traditional Milanese dishes are risotto alla milanese (a rice dish made with saffron) and cotoletta alla milanese (breaded veal). Milan has many fashionable restaurants serving modern Italian cuisine as well. Milanese bars often serve snacks with your before-dinner drink in the evening. A typical trattoria that I recommend in Milan is Trattoria Toscana di Giovanni.

If you want to stay near La Scala, the duomo, and shopping district, check these top rated historic center hotels.  One of the most luxurious hotels is the Four Seasons Hotel Milano, right in the fashion shopping district. Here are more Milan guest-rated and reviewed hotels on Venere.

Nightlife in Milan:

Milan is a good city for nightlife with many popular nightclubs, cinemas, and cultural events, including opera, ballet, concerts, and theater. The main theater and concert season starts in October but there are performances in summer, too. Check with one of the tourist offices or your hotel for the latest information.

Festivals in Milan:

Milan's biggest feast day for its patron saint, Saint Ambrose's Day, is December 7 with religious celebrations and a street fair. The Festa del Naviglio with parades, music, and other performances, is the first ten days of June. There are many fashion fairs, especially in fall.

Shopping in Milan:

Milan is a fashion lovers paradise so you will easily find top quality clothing, footwear, and accessories. Try Corso Vittorio Emanuele II near Piazza della Scala, via Monte Napoleone near the Duomo, or Via Dante between the Duomo and Castle. For exclusive fashions, try the area around via della Spiga called the Quadrilatero d'Oro. Corso Buenos Aires has many chain stores. Many shops are even open on Sunday on Corso Buenos Aires and Via Dante. Markets are held around the canals.

Milan Tourist Information Offices:

The main office is in Piazza del Duomo at Via Marconi 1. There is also a branch in the Central train station. The Milan City Council operates an information office in Galleria Vittorio Emanuele II, near the Piazza del Duomo, with information about cultural events.

What to See in Milan:

The small historic center is primarily between the Duomo and Castello. See also Top Milan Attractions and Picture Gallery

•	The Duomo is the world's largest Gothic cathedral and the third largest church in Europe. Building began in 1386 and lasted nearly 500 years! Its marble facade is magnificent and its roof has 135 spires and 3200 statues. Inside, the crucifix is said to contain a nail from the cross of Christ. Its piazza is the hub of Milan. There is also a museum. Be sure to climb the stairs or take the elevator to the top for views of Milan and the Duomo's spires. See pictures from the duomo rooftop.

•	La Scala is a very famous opera house seating over 2000 people. Built in 1778 it has a very opulent interior. You can also visit the museum.

•	Galleria Vittorio Emanuele II is a huge glass-roofed shopping arcade lined with expensive shops, bars, and restaurants. Built in 1867, it links the squares of the Duomo and La Scala and has mosaics with the symbols of the cities forming the newly united Italy. Some people consider it good luck to stand on the testicles of the bull of Turin.

•	Castello Sforzesco was originally built in the 15th century by the ruling Visconti but was destroyed and rebuilt by the Sforzas soon afterward. It became a museum complex in the 19th century and and is one of Milan's major landmarks.

•	Santa Maria della Grazie contains Da Vinci's famous fresco, the Last Supper. Although the building was bombed in 1943, the fresco survived. To visit, it is necessary to book in advance. How to Book Tickets to see The Last Supper.

•	National Museum of Science and Technology Leonardo da Vinci is housed in what was once a 16th century monastary . The museum has a vast collection showing the history of science and technology starting from Leonardo da Vinci's machines.

•	Sant'Ambrogio is the fourth-century church of Milan's patron saint. Inside are many relics, carvings, and mosaics.

•	Pinacoteca di Brera, originally started by Napolean, is Milan's most prestigious art gallery. It holds a huge collection of over 600 works in 40 rooms.

•	Milan makes a convenient base for day trips to the Lakes, Pavia, and the hill town of Bergamo. See Milan Day Trips for details and more day trip suggestions.
"</string>

</resources>
    
